Hello.
In this next lecture, we're going to make it so our mushroom character can actually fire and shoot
projectiles.
Our player character to get started.
Open up the mushroom animation source and set the mushroom range Attack animation.
So at this particular frame frame seven, I'm going have my mushroom launches projectile at the player
character.
So if we just right click and look for ADD, notify and select new notify.
And I'll just call this ranged attacks.
Next, if we just close this and go over to our mushroom animation blueprint.
In some free space, just right click and jump mode.
And call this attack.
And just drag up here and set animation state and I'm just going to call this my mushroom attack.
And if we double click and hence out it just right click and look for the play range attack animation.
So play much of the range attack or just hook this up here, then put this up to the idle.
So in order to transition from our mushroom attack back to our idol, we'll wait for this animation
to finish playing.
So I will just right click for time remaining.
And so that mushroom attack, if it is less than 0.1, we'll enter our transition again.
Next, if we head over to our mushroom blueprint.
Open it up and go over to the viewport tab.
And just go ahead and look for a scene.
Just rename us our spawn point.
And this is going to be where we spawn our projectile.
Just go over to select and translate objects.
And move this where you want the mushroom to spawn its projectile.
So I'm going to move it.
So it's kind of.
Right in front of its head.
So around here.
Next, I want you to go ahead and look for box collision.
And just move this box in front of our mushroom and make it quite wide in the x axis.
So something like this is fun and I'm going to make it quite tool in the Z axis as well.
And we'll make it so that one of our player character overlaps this box.
Our mushroom will start firing projectiles at them just so that we can see this box in our game.
And the details I'm going to look for hidden in game and neither unchecked.
Next.
If I scroll down and I go on component, we can overlap.
We can check to see if the other actor which entered this box is equal to my player character.
So look for equal and just get my player character.
If this condition is true.
So I look for a branch.
Then I'm going to just drag through and set a timer by event.
I'm not going to promote this to travel because when my Range Enemy attacks, it's just going to always
continue attacking no matter what.
So of of time put one and just check this looping box, then drag in our event and look for add custom
event and we'll call this mushroom attack.
And what this customer will do first will drag in our animation component and get our an instance.
And from here we'll cool our jump to node or chop to Node.
And the jump name.
I think I called it just a pack.
But let me check.
So I call that attack.
So here, under a Trump name, I'm going to attack.
And then the final thing we need to do is make the event which will spawned the projectile.
So if we just right click and add custom event and call it spawn projectile.
And when we file this note, we're going to drag up it and spawn actor prop cars.
The actor we're going to spawn is going to be the projectile that we made earlier.
And where we're going to spoon it.
Just right click on Swarm Transform.
Look for split structure pin.
And for the location, we just want to get wherever our spawn point is.
So just drag us in and we'll get world location.
And connect that into your location and pull the rotation so our projectiles wound in the correct rotation.
Just right click and we'll get actor rotation.
And hook us up here.
And for scale, we can just leave this at one, one, one.
There's one more thing we need to do, and that is head back to our mushroom animation program and go
over to the range attack.
And when we call this notifier, we want to drag off our mushroom and call the range attack custom event
that we just made sort of shrug off here and look for spawn projectile and connect this here and go
compile Now that close this and I go play.
And I walked into that box, the mushrooms would start firing projectiles at me.
So I go here.
They'll attack, they'll shoot me, and then I get damaged.
Nice.
Okay.
And one more thing.
If you wanted to adjust how fast it explodes the projectiles, you could change the time here.
So if I made something like 0.7, it's going to fire a lot faster.
Although one thing to keep in mind if you do this is we need to make sure that our mushroom attack emission
gets to the point where it fires the projectile.
So you may need to play around to get a value that you're happy with.
Hello.
So that's actually one more thing I forgot to do.
If I go play and I run into this box, my enemy will start shooting projectiles at me.
However, if I kill them, so I'm just going to kill my mushroom, it will still continue shooting at
us, even though it's dead.
So if we go back to our mushroom enemy.
And before we do the mushroom attack, let's just check that our mushroom is not dead.
If we go Branch.
And the condition of this grant is going to be that the mushroom is dead.
So if my mushroom is not dead, then we'll fire a projectile.
However, if my mushroom is dead, then we're going to do nothing.
So with that, we have finished the mushroom range enemy.
And whilst I'm here, I'm just going to come over the notes.
So I'll just comment this attack.
I will come at this event.
Begin play set up.
And I will just comment this.
Handle rotation.